Contact

hbcollins64@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/heather-collins-rn-msn-cnor-46123966 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Surgical Nursing

OR, ENDO, Sterile Processing Manager

Endoscopy

Certifications

CNOR

Heather Collins RN,MSN,CNOR

Assistant Clinical Director Perioperative Services at Texas Children's Hospital

Magnolia, Texas

Summary

Dedicated, staff and patient-focused nurse leader with proven strength in acute patient care, surgical services, staff development, family advocacy and high departmental quality outcomes.

Exceptional capacity to multi-task and manage, numerous and often competing priorities always putting high quality patient care at the forefront of every decision.

Ability to lead and motivate outstanding healthcare teams that provide high quality patient care.

Outstanding interpersonal and communication skills.

Knowledge and successful implementation of Joint Commission and DNV processes.

Experience in Acute care Hospital start up of the OR, Sterile Processing and Endoscopy Departments.

2010 Bravo Award

2013 Leader of the year

2013 Department of the Year

2016 Leadership Mission Award Recipient

2018 Leader Mission Award

2018 Blg Impact Award

CNOR

Medical Laser Safety Officer (MLSO)

Experience

Texas Children's Hospital Assistant Clinical Director Perioperative Services June 2019 - Present (1 year) West Campus

CHI St. Luke's Hospital at The Vintage

Director of Perioperative & CV Services October 2010 - June 2019 (8 years 9 months)

- * Responsible for the initial start up of the OR, Endoscopy and Sterile Processing departments
- * Responsible for the day to day operations of five OR suites, two endoscopy suites, Sterile Processing, Pre-op, PACU and Pre-Admission Testing, Cath Lab
- * Served as Interim CNO
- * Successfully developed and implemented CV Service Line
- * Liaison between the vendors and the facility
- * Coordinated installation of necessary equipment, supplies and instrumentation for all areas
- *Implemented CarePoint Program, Synergy and Sterilmed Programs to reduce cost and improve green initiatives
- * Circulate and scrub Surgery cases and Endoscopy
- * Responsible for yearly operational and capital budgets
- * Top department for employee engagement 6 years in a row
- * Maintained patient satisfaction scores above 90th % consistently
- * CNOR
- * MLSO (Medical Laser Safety Officer)
- * 2016-Responsible for implementation and start up of CVOR.
- * 2018 Implementation Total Joint Program
- * 2018 Chest Pain Accreditation

*

Dr. Pandya

RN

2007 - 2011 (4 years)

#Responsible for making daily patient rounds for physician in an in-patient hospital environment

#Assess and record all patient data both subjective and objective on a daily basis

#Write orders, dictate discharge and admission summaries for the physician under his supervision

Spring Creek Surgery Center

RN

May 2008 - October 2010 (2 years 6 months)

#Responsible for the day to day operations of multiple operating rooms

#Responsible for the care of patient's from multiple services and specialties including Endoscopy

#Provided Pre and Post operative nursing care

#Assist in the management of inventory levels and ordering of all pharmaceutical drugs and supplies necessary for all surgeries performed at the center

#Maintain and record all pathology reports for the center #Assist in the billing and charges for each surgical case

Tomball Regional Hospital

RN

May 2000 - May 2008 (8 years 1 month)

OR circulator / Endoscopy circulator

#Provided care of patient's in the surgical and Endoscopy departments

#Provided Pre and Post operative nursing care

#Assist in the billing and charges for each surgical case

#Provided Pre and Post operative nursing care

#Charge nurse in endo

Invitro-Fertilization Department Manager

#Responsible for the daily operations of the IVF department Cultivated and built client relations.

#Managed employees and addressed performance issues

#Ensured clinical quality and patient satisfaction thru ongoing performance initiatives and problem solving

#Hands on patient care and 24 hour call for emergencies

#Involved in hospital based committees and performance improvement

#Ordered and maintained all needed inventory for the department

Med-Surg/Pediatric RN Charge Nurse

Education

Chamberlain College of Nursing

MSN Executive Track / MBA, Nursing Administration · (2013 - 2015)

The University of Texas at Arlington

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2011 - 2012)

Houston Community College

Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1996 - 1998)